Jiabin Wang **Software Engineer**

in linkedin.com/in/jiabin-wang-32b031101

github.com/wibabc2015

1 +86-18975235693

@ jeremy.wangjb@outlook.com

i https://wjbabc2015.github.io/portfolio/



Seeking a software engineer where I can utilize my skills and experience in object-oriented design, mobile and web development, and machine learning research.

I have finished a Master of Science in Software Engineering in December 2016. I have two-year application development experience including mobile and web-based. In the meantime, I have one-year research experience in machine learning.

Skill Profile

Major Programming Technologies : XML, Javascript, CSS, PHP, HTML5, JAVA

> Database: MySQL, SQLITE

Development Tools: Visual Studio, Android Studio, Rational Software Architect, MATLAB/Octave, Eclipse, Sublime

Text 3, Microsoft Project and Office

¡Query, AJAX, C#, Machine Learning, Bootstrap, AngularJS Others:



Education

Master of Science in Software Engineering (MSSE), East Carolina University, USA

GPA: 3.62/4.0

Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering (BSEE), Central South University, China



Professional Experience

July 2017 April 2017

Web Developer(Part-time), Global Academic Initiatives, East Carolina University

- > Build web-based application running on MySOL from front-end to back-end for video uploading and database administration by using HTML, CSS, PHP and Jquery
- > Develop the front-end of the application based on the Bootstrap framework

HTML5 | CSS | Bootstrap | Javascript | PHP | MySQL | AJAX | JQuery | FuelPHP |

April 2017 August 2016

Research Assistant in machine learning, Department of Computer Science, East Carolina University

- > Delivered a JAVA application for processing diffraction images
- > Conducted Unit Testing for verifying the JAVA application
- > Developed an algorithm for image classification by using LIBSVM (an integrated software for SVM)
- > Contributed to two publications in IEEE

JAVA | Unit Testing | Support Vector Machine (SVM) | gray-level co-occurrence matrix (GLCM) | MATLAB/OCTAVE

August 2016 February 2016

Intern as Web Developer, Global Academic Initiatives, East Carolina University

- > Built a database driven website in PHP 5.3 running on MySQL from scratch
- > Developed complex SQL queries complemented with AJAX for information searching in the webbased application
- > Developed the application front-end in HTML5 complemented with CSS3, Javascript, and JQuery

HTML5 | CSS | Javascript | PHP | MySQL | AJAX | JQuery | Zend

February 2016 August 2015

Intern as Android App Developer, Department of Engineering, East Carolina University

- > Delivered a healthcare application connecting to the weight scale through IOIO board (an open source PIC microcontroller-based boards)
- > Built database within the application by using SQLITE
- > Developed application UI with XML
- > Developed application back-end with JAVA in Android Studio

JAVA XML SQLITE Android Studio



 $\textit{Delivered Website Link:} \quad \textit{http:} //\textit{hawk.aos.ecu.edu} \qquad \quad \textit{http:} //\textit{hawk.aos.ecu.edu} / \textit{videoupload}$

Certification AMERICAN SOFTWARE TESTING QUALIFICATIONS BOARD, INC.

Certified Tester, Foundation Level (CTFL), current

Publication: Building an SVM Classifier for Automated Selection of Big Data

http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/8029304/

Combinatorial Methods of Feature Selection for Cell Image Classification

http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/8004294/